[Music]
hi everyone this is Ravi welcome to
trien tasa automation
tutorial as you all know I've already
published around 40 YouTube videos
covering beginners intermediate and
advanced level Concepts in terms of
advanced level Concepts I already
published 25 YouTube
videos and from previous lesson onwards
I started you teaching the multi-user
workspace in the real time projects for
any given organization this is our
lesson 41 in terms of overall trient
tasa automation Concepts and this is
lesson 26 in terms of advanced level
Concepts in this lesson we going to
learn some more features that are
available for multi-user
workspace I'll Teach You How can we
manage users and user groups within the
workspace and how can you manage the
user
access for your project within the
workspace let us see the agenda
items so I'm going to teach you what are
the default user groups that are
available in your multi-user workspace
and how can we create new user groups
and how can we create the users within
the user
groups and how can we show disabled
enabled
users and how can you select the owning
group for the group that you
created and how can you delete the users
and user
groups and how can you provide the
access to the users at project level
object level and folder
level and how can you set the passwords
for the users that you have created
newly and how can you track the user
activity by using Create personal data
report please do subscribe to the
channel click on Bell icon you'll
receive notifications whenever I publish
more videos thank you now let us jump on
to the present
tasa so first default user groups first
of all to access the user groups and the
user management you need to select your
project so if you remember correctly in
our previous session we have created a
project called multi-user
demo so once you you select the project
you can see user management tab here the
right side details test configuration
properties definition and you have a
user management tab you need to select
user management Tab and if you see here
you already
have default user groups one is admins
and the second one is all users so these
are the default user
groups that you can see in your
workspace okay so these default user
groups generally contains admin's User
Group generally have a users related to
admin and all users means whatever's the
users that you add in any user group
right so those users will be displayed
under all users User Group okay so next
one is is create user
groups apart from these default user
groups let us say I want to create a new
user group so one thing is User Group
can be created based on the roles that
your team is playing or User Group can
be created based on the
project as well so let me create right
click how to create a user group you
need to right click on the project and
then first you need to check out your
project let me check out the project as
soon as you check out the project now
you will be able to edit or add all your
user groups okay so now right click and
let me create a new user group create
user group what I'm going to do I'm
going to create a new user group called
tasa specialist
okay this is one user group based on the
role I'm creating and then I would like
to create another user group right click
and
Taska design
specialist okay so these are the two
user groups that we created based on the
rules let's say there are some
organization which follow based on the
project as well project I can say
project
XYZ our project
multi-user
okay this is another project so that
means I created three different user
groups cor and then how can you create
the users within the user group let's
say I have tasar design specialist in my
team I have two design specialist so
what I'm going to do right click on this
and select create user I'm going to say
design I'll do one thing I'll just
mention design
specialist
one I'm just naming the user as design
One
Design specialist
2 okay and I want to create create Tas
Specialists right click under group
tasar
specialist specialist
01 specialist
02 okay this is how you can create the
user but whenever you create the user
you can either enable the user or
disable the user let's say I want to
disable design splist two you just need
to uncheck the Box okay and also you can
set result alow that
means if user can set the result
manually generally whenever you execute
the test cases the task
automatically set the result as pass or
fail based on the execution result right
but however if you want to override the
test result manually you can check the
check box let's say I don't want to give
any authority to set the result manually
for the test design Specialists because
they are going to just design them so
I'm going to remove these and I want to
keep the set result allowed manually
they can set the results to pass or fail
for the task C Specialists I want to
keep them and then level so you can
select the level of the axess whether
they want to have basic level of access
advanced level or expert level based on
the
level these users will be given the
permissions in
different module level okay so you can
select the levels here okay and then
owning group so owning group means let's
say this tasas specialist and tasas
design specialist okay I want to select
this owning group as all users owning
group this is all owners users owning
group and tasar specialist also I want
to select this as all users owning group
only let's say you have another uh let's
assume I want to create super user let
me create another group called super
users okay in this I'm going to create a
new user I created super users group
okay users group here I'm going to say
admin zero super user super
user 01 right now I want to give them as
expert as a level I want to enable the
group uh enable the user set result as
allowed and here this entire super User
Group owning group is admins that means
this group can be managed by only admins
okay that's why I selected owning group
as admins save this so now you
understand right once you create the
user groups how you should create a
users and how can you enable them set
results allowed and how can
you assign the owning group for
the user group that you created so that
means we created the users we select
owning group we also selected the owning
groups right now show disabled enabled
users so one more thing
here if I go to the tab view right let's
say I want to hide the disabled users if
you see
see design Splash list
2 is a disabled user so I don't want to
pay attention on this particular
disabled user right so I can simply
click on high disabled user so now you
see disabled users are hidden and show
disabled users this shows all disabled
as well as enabled users so
generally admin user does not want to
work on disabled users unless he wants
to enable right that's why we just I can
hide the disabled users by selecting the
option toggle option show disabled users
hi disable users so this is how you can
toggle the option and then delete users
and user groups how can you delete users
so let's say I want to delete this
disabled user you simply right click and
delete the user okay or I want to delete
the test design specialist user sorry
test design Specialist Group entire
group I can simply right click and click
on delete this will delete your entire
group but whenever I delete the entire
group but the users under design
specialist are still not yet deleted
right you can see I deleted the group
but I can see those users in all users
that
means if if you delete the group The
users under the group will not be
deleted if you want to delete the users
under the group you have to come to all
users right click and delete
or you can disable them simply you can
simply disable them you can simply
disable them this way you
can these users no longer can access
this work space
repository okay so that is done and next
one user access at project object and
folder level now let's say now we have
total specialist level specialist 01
specialist 02 super user 01 right these
are all the enabled users now I want to
provide access to these
users for my project how can I do that
so let's say I want to go to test case
section and you need to expand this
properties
section so if you see here let's say
this particular test case
section can
be viewed
by which users I can provide here
viewing group name so let me first of
all check out this let me check out this
entire tree right now
here I want to give view access to all
users simply select all users group I'm
selecting all users group if you
remember correctly this all User Group
you already have right one default all
user group right so I am
providing access to every everyone to
view this
section what about the owning group who
can edit this test case section I want
to provide the owning group as Tas
Specialist Group tasa specialist that
means the users who are in tasa
Specialist Group can work on this
particular test case section
okay so this is way I can enable access
for each and every User Group okay let's
assume for execution right for the
execution or sorry not for the execution
let us assume for modules even for
modules right click and check out for
this modules as well I can give viewing
group permission to all users
but owning group who can edit add the
objects to the modules are Tasco
specialist okay and then configuration
for example I want to give access to
this configurations so these
configurations where I can add DE agents
I can configure the agents right I can
configure the database I want to give VI
to
everyone all users but this owning
group so who can edit who can add agents
and manage agents are only admin that is
super users I want to select super super
users as owning group name that means
the users who are under super users
group can only edit add the
details under
configurations okay that is done so this
is how you can manage access at folder
level object level so you if you want to
give only to particular object like test
case one you can provide that way also
so whatever the level you want to
provide you can folder level you can
provide entire project level you can
provide uh the access right whatever the
component level you want you can provide
the access at component level
and then set password for users let's go
back to again project go to user
management now if I want to set the
password for specialist
01 this is the user and I can set the
password for this user right click and
click on set
password let's say I can
say I can just set the password and
click on okay and again confirm click on
okay so now whenever this specialist 01
user logs into this workspace he has to
use the password that I set up that
means admin generally sets the password
for every
user okay admin user set the password
and that password will be given to the
particular team member called specialist
01 so that he can log into the password
and you can also remove or modified the
password or you can remove the password
also by
using set
password okay and then the next one is
track user
activity let's say I want to track the
user activity of uh specialist 02 how
can I do do that right click and then
click on create personal data report as
soon as I click on create personal data
report it creates an Excel sheet okay
here so this is a specialist 01 user
data
report probably this will have empty
rows because we haven't done this user
did not log to the workspace and he
haven't done any
activities let's go back here I want to
generate
the user
activity create personal data report for
admin let's do this now right click and
create personal data report this will
export your Excel sheet to this
particular folder see now so this is my
personal data report for the admin now
this will have all the activities that
admin has performed so let's see here
now okay let's Analyze This what do you
have so this user accessed this Min
machine and this workspace and this is
the user ID and this is the username and
what is the revision of this particular
object right and
then what is the date that he modified
and what is the object he modified what
is the object ID and what is the
revision 15th revision 17th revision
right so you can access personal data
report for every user so that you can
track the activity of that particular
user in this particular workspace or the
repository
okay so these are all the
activities that you can perform so this
is how you can manage the
users you can manage the user groups can
manage the
access levels for the group I mean for
the users that you
created okay hope you all understand the
concepts of managing the users managing
the user groups at project level folder
level at any component level that you
want so if you have any queries leave
your queries in the comment box I'll try
to respond to your queries thank you
hope you all understand the concepts of
managing users and user groups in
multi-user
workspace so you have learned how can
you create different users and then how
can you create different user groups and
then how can you provide access for
different users and different user
groups at project level at object level
and at entire folder
level please do subscribe to the channel
click on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos thank
[Music]
you